<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
<!--Begin Generated Intro Tag (DO NOT REMOVE)-->
"Must Have", "QI Elements" and "primary code path" are defined in the <a href="index.html#mustsupport-flag">QI-Core Must Support section</a>.<br></br>

<b>QI Elements:</b>
<ul>
<li>medication[x]: (QI) What was administered</li>
<li>dosage: (QI) Details of how medication was taken</li>
<li>statusReason: (QI) Reason administration not performed</li>
<li>medication[x].extension(codeOptions): (QI) Url of a value set of candidate medications</li>
<li>subject: (QI) Who received medication</li>
<li>request: (QI) Request administration performed against</li>
<li>effective[x]: (QI) Start and end time of administration</li>
<li>status: (QI) not-done</li>
<li>context: (QI) Encounter or Episode of Care administered as part of</li>
</ul>

<b>Primary code path:</b> medication
<br></br>
(PCPath) This element is the primary code path for this resource <a href='https://cql.hl7.org/02-authorsguide.html#retrieve'>CQL Retrieve</a>
<br></br>
<br></br>

<!--End Generated Intro (DO NOT REMOVE)-->
  <a name="usage"><b>Usage</b></a>

<p>The MedicationAdministration profile defines the conformance expectations for a MedicationAdministration event, 
regardless of whether it is a positive or negative statement. The MedicationAdministrationDone and MedicationAdministrationNotDone 
profiles represent the positive and negative statements for a MedicationAdministration event.</p>

<p>To create an expression indicating existence of a MedicationAdministration, use the profile <a href="StructureDefinition-qicore-medicationadministrationdone.html">QICoreMedicationAdministrationDone</a>; to specifically request information that a MedicationAdministration intentionally
did not occur for a medical, patient or system reason, use the profile <a href="StructureDefinition-qicore-medicationadministrationnotdone.html">QICoreMedicationAdministrationNotDone</a>.</p>

  <p>The following example illustrates an expression to retrieve instances that meet measure intent for exclusion:</p>

  <pre><code>define "Low Dose Unfractionated Heparin for VTE Prophylaxis Not Administered":
  ["MedicationAdministrationNotDone": "Low Dose Unfractionated Heparin for VTE Prophylaxis"] VTEMedication
    where VTEMedication.category ~ QICoreCommon."Inpatient"
      and (VTEMedication.reasonCode in "Medical Reason" or VTEMedication.reasonCode in "Patient Refusal")</code></pre>

  <p>For a more complete discussion of representation of negation within QI-Core and quality improvement artifacts, see the <a href="negation.html">Negation in QI-Core</a> topic.</p>

  <p>
  <tr>
      <td>See the <a href="patterns.html">patterns</a> page for implementation and usage patterns.</td>
  </tr>
</p>
  <a name="examples"> </a>
  <h3>Examples</h3>
  <p>
  <table>
    <tbody>
      <tr>
        <td><a href="MedicationAdministration-negation-example.html">Negation example using a valueset</a></td><td>Medication not administered using a value set to indicate what was not administered; indicates that none of the medications in the given value set were administered</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td><a href="MedicationAdministration-negation-with-code-example.html">Negation example using a code</a></td><td>Medication not administered using a code to indicate that a particular medication was not administered; indicates that a specific medication, by code, was not administered</td>
      </tr>
    </tbody>
  </table>
  </p>

</div>
