<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
<!--Begin Generated Intro Tag (DO NOT REMOVE)-->
<b>Must Have:</b>
<ul>
<li>identifier.system: The namespace for the identifier value</li>
<li>identifier.value: The value that is unique</li>
<li>status: (QI) planned | arrived | triaged | in-progress | onleave | finished | cancelled +</li>
<li>class: Classification of patient encounter</li>
<li>type: (QI) Specific type of encounter</li>
<li>subject: (QI) The patient or group present at the encounter</li>
<li>location.location: (QI) Location the encounter takes place</li>
</ul>

<b>QI Elements:</b>
<ul>
<li>participant: (QI) List of participants involved in the encounter</li>
<li>participant.individual: (QI) Persons involved in the encounter other than the patient</li>
<li>period: (QI) The start and end time of the encounter</li>
<li>reasonCode: (QI) Coded reason the encounter takes place</li>
<li>reasonReference: (QI) Reason the encounter takes place (reference)</li>
<li>hospitalization: (QI) Details about the admission to a healthcare service</li>
<li>hospitalization.dischargeDisposition: (QI) Category or kind of location after discharge</li>
<li>location: (QI) List of locations where the patient has been</li>
<li>location.period: (QI) Time period during which the patient was present at the location</li>
<li>serviceProvider: (QI) The organization (facility) responsible for this encounter</li>
</ul>

<b>Primary code path:</b> type
<br></br>
(PCPath) This element is the primary code path for this resource <a href='https://cql.hl7.org/02-authorsguide.html#filtering-with-terminology'>CQL Retrieve</a>
<br></br>
<br></br>

<br></br>
<b>NOTE TO BALLOT REVIEWERS:</b>
<ul>
<li>US Core 7.0, and thus QI-Core 7.0, has a new approach to USCDI requirements.</li>
<ul>
<li>As noted in the US Core 7.0 <a href='https://hl7.org/fhir/us/core/must-support.html#must-support-elements'>Must Support</a> section, US Core 7.0 no longer highlights mandatory (cardinality 1..* or 1..1) and Must Support elements with a (USCDI) indicator as such items must be supported for interoperability.</li>
<li>Those USCDI elements that are not mandatory or Must Support now include an indicator (ADDITIONAL USCDI) in US Core. QI-Core 7.0 does not reference USCDI elements; rather, users should access US Core 7.0 to understand its implementation of USCDI version 4.</li>
</ul>
<li>We invite comments about the approach and suggestions for other options that would also avoid unnecessary noise or reading load to the QI-Core profile representation.</li>
<li>Further, QI-Core 7.0 does not discuss <a href='https://uscdiplus.healthit.gov/uscdi'>USCDI+Quality</a> because at the time of ballot preparation, no published version of USCDI+Quality is available. We seek reviewer advice regarding how QI-Core might address future USCDI+Quality.</li>
</ul>
<br></br>


<!--End Generated Intro (DO NOT REMOVE)-->
<a name="usage"><b>Usage</b></a>
<p>The following example illustrates accessing an inpatient encounter:</p>

<pre>
<code>define "Ophthalmology Encounter Codes":
  [Encounter: class in "Inpatient Encounter Classes"] InpatientEncounter
    where InpatientEncounter.type in "Ophthalmology Encounter Codes"</code>
</pre>

<p>
<tr>
    <td>See the <a href="patterns.html">patterns</a> page for implementation and usage patterns.</td>
</tr>
</p>
<a name="examples"> </a>
<h3>Examples</h3>
<p>
<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
        <td><a href="Encounter-example.html">Inpatient Admission for Appendicitis</a></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
</p>

</div>
