<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
<!--Begin Generated Intro Tag (DO NOT REMOVE)-->
<b>QI Elements:</b>
<ul>
<li>notDoneReason: (QI) Extension</li>
<li>status: (QI) registered | preliminary | final | amended +</li>
<li>category: (QI) Classification of type of observation</li>
<li>code: (QI) Type of observation (code / type)</li>
<li>notDoneValueSet: (QI) What was not done</li>
<li>subject: (QI) Who and/or what the observation is about</li>
<li>effective[x]: (QI) Clinically relevant time/time-period for observation</li>
<li>issued: (QI) Date/Time this version was made available</li>
<li>value[x]: (QI) Actual result</li>
<li>value[x]: (QI) Actual result</li>
<li>interpretation: (QI) High, low, normal, etc.</li>
</ul>

<b>Primary code path:</b> code
<br></br>
(PCPath) This element is the primary code path for this resource <a href='https://cql.hl7.org/02-authorsguide.html#filtering-with-terminology'>CQL Retrieve</a>
<br></br>
<br></br>

<br></br>
<b>NOTE TO BALLOT REVIEWERS:</b>
<ul>
<li>US Core 7.0, and thus QI-Core 7.0, has a new approach to USCDI requirements.</li>
<ul>
<li>As noted in the US Core 7.0 <a href='https://hl7.org/fhir/us/core/must-support.html#must-support-elements'>Must Support</a> section, US Core 7.0 no longer highlights mandatory (cardinality 1..* or 1..1) and Must Support elements with a (USCDI) indicator as such items must be supported for interoperability.</li>
<li>Those USCDI elements that are not mandatory or Must Support now include an indicator (ADDITIONAL USCDI) in US Core. QI-Core 7.0 does not reference USCDI elements; rather, users should access US Core 7.0 to understand its implementation of USCDI version 4.</li>
</ul>
<li>We invite comments about the approach and suggestions for other options that would also avoid unnecessary noise or reading load to the QI-Core profile representation.</li>
<li>Further, QI-Core 7.0 does not discuss <a href='https://uscdiplus.healthit.gov/uscdi'>USCDI+Quality</a> because at the time of ballot preparation, no published version of USCDI+Quality is available. We seek reviewer advice regarding how QI-Core might address future USCDI+Quality.</li>
</ul>
<br></br>


<!--End Generated Intro (DO NOT REMOVE)-->
  <a name="usage"><b>Usage</b></a>
  <p>
  <tr>
      <td>See the <a href="patterns.html">patterns</a> page for implementation and usage patterns.</td>
  </tr>
  </p>

<p>The Simple Observation and ObservationCancelled profiles represent the positive and
  negative statements for an observation. To ensure instances retrieved meet
  negative intent, applications should check the status element as illustrated in
  this example:</p>

<pre>
<code>define "Pap Test Refused":
  ["ObservationCancelled": "Pap Test"] PapTest
    where PapTest.notDoneReason in "Patient Refusal"</code>
</pre>

<p>Note that when a more specific observation, such as a Blood Pressure, is negated, the
	resource instance should conform to both the specific observation profile AND the
	general negation profile.</p>

  <a name="examples"> </a>
  <h3>Examples</h3>
  <p>
  <table>
    <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td><a href="Observation-negation-example.html">Negation Example with valueset</a></td><td>Observation not indicated; indicates that none of the observations in the given not done value set were performed.</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td><a href="Observation-negation-with-code-example.html">Negation Example with code</a></td><td>Observation not indicate; indicates that a specific observation, by code, was not done.</td>
      </tr>
    </tbody>
  </table>
  </p>

  <p>For a more complete discussion of representation of negation within QI-Core and quality improvement artifacts, see the <a href="index.html#negation-in-qi-core">Negation in QI-Core</a> topic.</p>

</div>
