<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
<a name="guidance"></a>
<h3>Guidance</h3>
<p>
<tr>
    <td>Reference Guidance for use of the Service Request profile can be found <a href="{{site.data.fhir.ver.uscore}}/StructureDefinition-us-core-servicerequest.html#mandatory-and-must-support-data-elements">here.</a></td>
    <ul><li>See the <a href="https://hl7.org/fhir/us/core/sdoh.html">Social Determinants of Health (SDOH)</a> Guidance Page for more information when exchanging Social Determinants of Health (SDOH) Service Requests.</li>
    <li>The <code class="highlighter-rouge">ServiceRequest.category</code> binding must support at a minimum the <a href="{{site.data.fhir.ver.uscore}}/ValueSet-us-core-servicerequest-category.html">US Core ServiceRequest Category Codes</a>.  However, this valueset can be treated as <a href="http://hl7.org/fhir/R4/terminologies.html#extensible">extensible</a> and other category codes can be used instead.</li>
    <li>The <code class="highlighter-rouge">ServiceRequest.code</code> valueset is broad to accommodate a wide variety of use cases and should be constrained to a subset for a particular use case or domain. (for example, LOINC for laboratory orders.)</li>
    <li>The <code class="highlighter-rouge">ServiceRequest.subject</code> is Must Support with Must Support reference to QI Core Patient</li></ul>
</tr>
</p>

<a name="usage"><b>Usage</b></a>
<p>To create an expression specifically requesting information that a ServiceRequest intentionally did
not occur for a medical, patient or system reason, use the profile <a href="StructureDefinition-qicore-servicenotrequested.html">QICore-Servicenotrequested</a>.</p>
<p>The ServiceRequest and ServiceNotRequested profiles represent the positive and
  negative statements for a service request. To ensure instances retrieved meet
  positive intent, applications should check the status and doNotPerform elements as illustrated in
  this example:</p>

<pre>
<code>define ServiceRequest:
  [ServiceRequest] SR
    where SR.status in { 'draft', 'active', 'on-hold', 'completed' }
      and SR.doNotPerform is not true
</code>
</pre>

<p>The following example illustrates the use of the ServiceRequest profile:</p>

<pre>
<code>define "Intervention Comfort Measures":
  (["ServiceRequest": "Comfort Measures"] P
    where P.intent = 'order'
      and P.doNotPerform is not true
  )
    union (["Procedure": "Comfort Measures"] InterventionPerformed
      where InterventionPerformed.status in {'completed', 'in-progress'}
    )
</code>
</pre>

<p>
<tr>
    <td>See the <a href="patterns.html">patterns</a> page for implementation and usage patterns.</td>
</tr>
</p>
<a name="examples"> </a>
<h3>Examples</h3>
<p>
<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
        <td><a href="ServiceRequest-example.html">Request for Appendectomy Example</a></td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td><a href="ServiceRequest-referral-example.html">Referral for Procedure Example</a></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
</p>

</div>
