<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
<!--Begin Generated Intro Tag (DO NOT REMOVE)-->
<b>Must Have:</b>
<ul>
<li>questionnaire: Form being answered</li>
<li>status: in-progress | completed | amended | entered-in-error | stopped</li>
<li>subject: (QI) The subject of the questions</li>
<li>authored: Date the answers were gathered</li>
<li>item.linkId: (QI) Pointer to specific item from Questionnaire</li>
</ul>

<b>QI Elements:</b>
<ul>
<li>author: (QI) Person who received and recorded the answers</li>
<li>item: (QI) Groups and questions</li>
<li>item.answer.value[x]: (QI) Single-valued answer to the question</li>
</ul>

<br></br>
<b>NOTE TO BALLOT REVIEWERS:</b>
<ul>
<li>US Core 7.0, and thus QI-Core 7.0, has a new approach to USCDI requirements.</li>
<ul>
<li>As noted in the US Core 7.0 <a href='https://hl7.org/fhir/us/core/must-support.html#must-support-elements'>Must Support</a> section, US Core 7.0 no longer highlights mandatory (cardinality 1..* or 1..1) and Must Support elements with a (USCDI) indicator as such items must be supported for interoperability.</li>
<li>Those USCDI elements that are not mandatory or Must Support now include an indicator (ADDITIONAL USCDI) in US Core. QI-Core 7.0 does not reference USCDI elements; rather, users should access US Core 7.0 to understand its implementation of USCDI version 4.</li>
</ul>
<li>We invite comments about the approach and suggestions for other options that would also avoid unnecessary noise or reading load to the QI-Core profile representation.</li>
<li>Further, QI-Core 7.0 does not discuss <a href='https://uscdiplus.healthit.gov/uscdi'>USCDI+Quality</a> because at the time of ballot preparation, no published version of USCDI+Quality is available. We seek reviewer advice regarding how QI-Core might address future USCDI+Quality.</li>
</ul>
<br></br>


<!--End Generated Intro (DO NOT REMOVE)-->
  <a name="guidance"></a>
  <h3>Guidance</h3>
  <p>
  <tr>
      <td>Reference Guidance for use of the QuestionnaireResponse profile can be found <a href="{{site.data.fhir.ver.uscore}}/StructureDefinition-us-core-questionnaireresponse.html#mandatory-and-must-support-data-elements">here.</a></td>
      <ul><li>See the <a href="https://hl7.org/fhir/us/core/sdoh.html">Social Determinants of Health (SDOH)</a> Guidance Page for how this profile <i>along with other Observation Profiles or alternatively QuestionnaireResponse</i> to is used represent SDOH assessments.</li></ul>
  </tr>
  </p>
  <a name="usage"><b>Usage</b></a>
  <p>
  <tr>
      <td>See the <a href="patterns.html">patterns</a> page for implementation and usage patterns.</td>
  </tr>
  </p>
  <a name="examples"> </a>
  <h3>Examples</h3>
  <p>
  <table>
    <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td><a href="QuestionnaireResponse-PHQ-9-example.html">PHQ-9 QuestionnaireResponse Example</a></td>
        </tr>
    </tbody>
  </table>
  </p>



</div>
