<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
<!--Begin Generated Intro Tag (DO NOT REMOVE)-->
"Must Have", "QI Elements" and "primary code path" are defined in the <a href="index.html#mustsupport-flag">QI-Core Must Support section</a>.<br></br>

<b>Must Have:</b>
<ul>
<li>subject: (QI) Who or group medication request is for</li>
<li>status: (QI) active | on-hold | cancelled | completed | stopped | draft</li>
<li>intent: (QI) proposal | plan | order | original-order | reflex-order | filler-order | instance-order | option</li>
<li>medication[x]: (QI) Medication to be taken</li>
</ul>

<b>QI Elements:</b>
<ul>
<li>doNotPerform: (QI) True if medication was not requested</li>
<li>reasonCode: (QI) Reason or indication for ordering or not ordering the medication</li>
<li>category: (QI) Type of medication usage</li>
<li>authoredOn: (QI) When request was initially authored</li>
<li>requester: (QI) Who/What requested the Request</li>
<li>extension(medicationAdherence): (QI) Reported adherence to prescribed medication instructions.</li>
<li>encounter: (QI) Encounter created as part of encounter/admission/stay</li>
<li>dispenseRequest: (QI) Medication supply authorization</li>
<li>reasonReference: (QI) QI-Core Condition or Observation that supports the prescription</li>
<li>dosageInstruction: (QI) How medication should be taken</li>
<li>reported[x]: (QI) Reported rather than primary record</li>
</ul>

<b>Primary code path:</b> medication
<br></br>
(PCPath) This element is the primary code path for this resource <a href='https://cql.hl7.org/02-authorsguide.html#retrieve'>CQL Retrieve</a>
<br></br>
<br></br>

<!--End Generated Intro (DO NOT REMOVE)-->
  <a name="usage"><b>Usage</b></a>

  <p>The MedicationRequest profile defines the conformance expectations for a MedicationRequest, 
  regardless of whether it is a positive or negative statement. The MedicationRequested and MedicationNotRequested 
  profiles represent the positive and negative statements for a medication order.</p>

<p>To create an expression indicating the existence of a medication request, use the profile <a href="StructureDefinition-qicore-medicationrequested.html">QICoreMedicationRequested</a>; to specifically request information that a MedicationRequest intentionally did not occur for a medical, patient or system reason, use the profile <a href="StructureDefinition-qicore-medicationprohibited.html">QICoreMedicationProhibited</a>.</p>

<p>The following example illustrates the use of the MedicationRequest profile:</p>
<pre>
<code>define "Antithrombotic Therapy at Discharge":
  ["MedicationRequested": medication in "Antithrombotic Therapy"] Antithrombotic
    where (Antithrombotic.isCommunity() or Antithrombotic.isDischarge())
      and Antithrombotic.intent = 'order'</code>
</pre>

<p>Note that the doNotPerform and statuses indicating positive intent are implied by the use of the MedicationRequested profile.</p>

  <p>
  <tr>
      <td>See the <a href="patterns.html">patterns</a> page for implementation and usage patterns.</td>
  </tr>
  </p>
  <a name="examples"> </a>
  <h3>Examples</h3>
  <p>
  <table>
    <tbody>
      <tr>
        <td><a href="MedicationRequest-requested-example.html">Penicillin MedicationRequest Example</a></td>
      </tr>
    </tbody>
  </table>
  </p>

</div>
