<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
<!--Begin Generated Intro Tag (DO NOT REMOVE)-->
<b>Must Have:</b>
<ul>
<li>identifier: An identifier for this patient</li>
<li>identifier.system: The namespace for the identifier value</li>
<li>identifier.value: The value that is unique within the system.</li>
<li>name: A name associated with the patient</li>
<li>telecom.system: phone | fax | email | pager | url | sms | other</li>
<li>telecom.value: The actual contact point details</li>
<li>gender: male | female | other | unknown</li>
<li>communication.language: The language which can be used to communicate with the patient about his or her health</li>
</ul>

<b>QI Elements:</b>
<ul>
<li>race: (QI) US Core Race Extension</li>
<li>ethnicity: (QI) US Core ethnicity Extension</li>
<li>tribalAffiliation: (QI) Tribal Affiliation Extension</li>
<li>sex: (QI) Sex Extension</li>
<li>genderIdentity: (QI) The individual's gender identity</li>
<li>name.use: (QI) usual | official | temp | nickname | anonymous | old | maiden</li>
<li>name.suffix: (QI) Parts that come after the name</li>
<li>name.period: (QI) Time period when name was/is in use</li>
<li>telecom: (QI) A contact detail for the individual</li>
<li>birthDate: (QI) The date of birth for the individual</li>
<li>deceased[x]: (QI) Indicates if the individual is deceased or not</li>
<li>address: (QI) An address for the individual</li>
<li>address.use: (QI) home | work | temp | old | billing - purpose of this address</li>
<li>address.period: (QI) Time period when address was/is in use</li>
<li>communication: (QI) A language which may be used to communicate with the patient about his or her health</li>
</ul>

<br></br>
<b>NOTE TO BALLOT REVIEWERS:</b>
<ul>
<li>US Core 7.0, and thus QI-Core 7.0, has a new approach to USCDI requirements.</li>
<ul>
<li>As noted in the US Core 7.0 <a href='https://hl7.org/fhir/us/core/must-support.html#must-support-elements'>Must Support</a> section, US Core 7.0 no longer highlights mandatory (cardinality 1..* or 1..1) and Must Support elements with a (USCDI) indicator as such items must be supported for interoperability.</li>
<li>Those USCDI elements that are not mandatory or Must Support now include an indicator (ADDITIONAL USCDI) in US Core. QI-Core 7.0 does not reference USCDI elements; rather, users should access US Core 7.0 to understand its implementation of USCDI version 4.</li>
</ul>
<li>We invite comments about the approach and suggestions for other options that would also avoid unnecessary noise or reading load to the QI-Core profile representation.</li>
<li>Further, QI-Core 7.0 does not discuss <a href='https://uscdiplus.healthit.gov/uscdi'>USCDI+Quality</a> because at the time of ballot preparation, no published version of USCDI+Quality is available. We seek reviewer advice regarding how QI-Core might address future USCDI+Quality.</li>
</ul>
<br></br>


<!--End Generated Intro (DO NOT REMOVE)-->
  <a name="usage"><b>Usage</b></a>
  <p>
  <tr>
      <td>See the <a href="patterns.html">patterns</a> page for implementation and usage patterns.</td>
  </tr>
  </p>
  <a name="examples"> </a>
  <h3>Examples</h3>
  <p>
  <table>
    <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td><a href="Patient-example.html">Basic Patient Example</a></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td><a href="Patient-example-2.html">65+ Female Patient Example</a></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td><a href="Patient-infant-example.html">Infant Patient Example</a></td>
      </tr>
    </tbody>
  </table>
  </p>

</div>
