<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
  <a name="usage"><b>Usage</b></a>
  <p>
  <tr>
      <td>See the <a href="patterns.html">patterns</a> page for implementation and usage patterns.</td>
  </tr>
</p>

<p>The MedicationAdministration and MedicationNotAdministered profiles represent the positive and
  negative statements for a medication administration. To ensure instances retrieved meet
  positive intent, applications should check the status element as illustrated in
  this example:</p>

<pre><code>define MedicationAdministrationNotDone:
  [MedicationAdministration] M
    where M.status = 'not-done'</code></pre>

  <p>The following example illustrates accessing MedicationAdministration not done data:</p>
<pre>
<code>// connectathon/fhir4/cql/EXM108_FHIR4-8.2.000.cql
define "No Low Dose Unfractionated Heparin Administration":
  ["MedicationAdministration": medication in "Low Dose Unfractionated Heparin for VTE Prophylaxis"] VTEMedication
    where VTEMedication.status = 'not-done'
</code>
</pre>
  <a name="examples"> </a>
  <h3>Examples</h3>
  <p>
  <table>
    <tbody>
      <tr>
        <td><a href="MedicationAdministration-negation-example.html">Negation example using a valueset</a></td><td>Medication not administered using a value set to indicate what was not administered; indicates that none of the medications in the given value set were administered</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td><a href="MedicationAdministration-negation-with-code-example.html">Negation example using a code</a></td><td>Medication not administered using a code to indicate that a particular medication was not administered; indicates that a specific medication, by code, was not administered</td>
      </tr>
    </tbody>
  </table>
  </p>

  <p>Both of these example instances meet measure intent for exclusion as defined in the following example CQL:
  </p>

  <pre><code>define "No VTE Prophylaxis Medication Administered or Ordered":
    ( ["MedicationAdministration": "Low Dose Unfractionated Heparin for VTE Prophylaxis"]
      union ["MedicationAdministration": "Low Molecular Weight Heparin for VTE Prophylaxis"]
      union ["MedicationAdministration": "Injectable Factor Xa Inhibitor for VTE Prophylaxis"]
      union ["MedicationAdministration": "Warfarin"]
      union ["MedicationAdministration": "Rivaroxaban for VTE Prophylaxis"]
    ) MedicationAdm
      let MedicationNotDoneTiming: Global.GetExtension ( MedicationAdm, 'qicore-recorded' ).value
      where MedicationAdm.status = 'not-done'
      return {
        id: MedicationAdm.id,
        MedicationStatusReason: MedicationAdm.statusReason,
        authoredOn: MedicationNotDoneTiming
      }</code></pre>

  <p>For a more complete discussion of representation of negation within QICore and quality improvement artifacts, see the <a href="index.html#negation-in-qi-core">Negation in QI Core</a> topic.</p>

</div>
