<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
<!--Begin Generated Intro Tag (DO NOT REMOVE)-->
"Must Have", "QI Elements" and "primary code path" are defined in the <a href="index.html#mustsupport-flag">QI-Core Must Support section</a>.<br></br>

<b>Must Have:</b>
<ul>
<li>subject: (QI) Who the procedure was performed on</li>
<li>code: (QI) What procedure</li>
<li>status: (QI) preparation | in-progress | not-done | on-hold | stopped | completed | entered-in-error | unknown</li>
</ul>

<b>QI Elements:</b>
<ul>
<li>performed[x]: (QI) When the procedure was performed</li>
<li>reasonCode: (QI) Coded reason procedure performed</li>
<li>reasonReference: (QI) The justification that the procedure was performed</li>
<li>basedOn: (QI) A request for this procedure</li>
<li>code.extension(codeOptions): (QI) Url of a value set of candidate procedures</li>
<li>extension(recorded): (QI) When the procedure was first captured in the subject's record</li>
</ul>

<b>Primary code path:</b> code
<br></br>
(PCPath) This element is the primary code path for this resource <a href='https://cql.hl7.org/02-authorsguide.html#retrieve'>CQL Retrieve</a>
<br></br>
<br></br>

<!--End Generated Intro (DO NOT REMOVE)-->
	<a name="usage"><b>Usage</b></a>

  <p>The Procedure profile defines the conformance expectations for a Procedure, 
  regardless of whether it is a positive or negative statement. The ProcedureDone and ProcedureNotDone 
  profiles represent the positive and negative statements for a procedure.</p>

	<p>To create an expression indicating existence of a procedure, use the profile <a href="StructureDefinition-qicore-proceduredone.html">QICoreProcedureDone</a>; to specifically request information that a procedure intentionally did not occur for
	a medical, patient or system reason, use the profile <a href="StructureDefinition-qicore-procedurenotdone.html">QICoreProcedureNotDone</a>.</p>

<p>The following example illustrates the use of the Procedure profile:</p>

<pre>
<code>define "Application of Intermittent Pneumatic Compression Devices":
  ["Procedure": "Application of Intermittent Pneumatic Compression Devices (IPC)"] DeviceApplied
    where DeviceApplied.status = 'completed'</code>
</pre>
	<p>
   <tr>
       <td>See the <a href="patterns.html">patterns</a> page for implementation and usage patterns.</td>
   </tr>
   </p>
   <a name="examples"> </a>
   <h3>Examples</h3>
   <p>
   <table>
     <tbody>
			 <tr>
			     <td><a href="Procedure-example.html">Appendectomy Example</a></td>
			 </tr>
     </tbody>
   </table>
   </p>


</div>
