<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
<!--Begin Generated Intro Tag (DO NOT REMOVE)-->
<b>Must Have:</b>
<ul>
<li>status: (QI) draft | active | on-hold | revoked | completed | entered-in-error | unknown</li>
<li>intent: (QI) proposal | plan | directive | order | original-order | reflex-order | filler-order | instance-order | option</li>
<li>code: What is being requested/ordered</li>
<li>subject: (QI) Individual or Entity the service is ordered for</li>
<li>authoredOn: (QI) Date request signed</li>
</ul>

<b>QI Elements:</b>
<ul>
<li>reasonRefused: (QI) Extension</li>
<li>doNotPerform: (QI) True if service/procedure should not be performed</li>
<li>notDoneValueSet: (QI) What was not requested</li>
<li>occurrence[x]: (QI) When service should occur</li>
<li>reasonCode: (QI) Explanation/Justification for procedure or service</li>
<li>reasonReference: (QI) Explanation/Justification for service or service</li>
</ul>

<b>Primary code path:</b> code
<br></br>
(PCPath) This element is the primary code path for this resource <a href='https://cql.hl7.org/02-authorsguide.html#filtering-with-terminology'>CQL Retrieve</a>
<br></br>
<br></br>

<br></br>
<b>NOTE TO BALLOT REVIEWERS:</b>
<ul>
<li>US Core 7.0, and thus QI-Core 7.0, has a new approach to USCDI requirements.</li>
<ul>
<li>As noted in the US Core 7.0 <a href='https://hl7.org/fhir/us/core/must-support.html#must-support-elements'>Must Support</a> section, US Core 7.0 no longer highlights mandatory (cardinality 1..* or 1..1) and Must Support elements with a (USCDI) indicator as such items must be supported for interoperability.</li>
<li>Those USCDI elements that are not mandatory or Must Support now include an indicator (ADDITIONAL USCDI) in US Core. QI-Core 7.0 does not reference USCDI elements; rather, users should access US Core 7.0 to understand its implementation of USCDI version 4.</li>
</ul>
<li>We invite comments about the approach and suggestions for other options that would also avoid unnecessary noise or reading load to the QI-Core profile representation.</li>
<li>Further, QI-Core 7.0 does not discuss <a href='https://uscdiplus.healthit.gov/uscdi'>USCDI+Quality</a> because at the time of ballot preparation, no published version of USCDI+Quality is available. We seek reviewer advice regarding how QI-Core might address future USCDI+Quality.</li>
</ul>
<br></br>


<!--End Generated Intro (DO NOT REMOVE)-->
  <a name="guidance"></a>
  <h3>Guidance</h3>
  <p>
  <tr>
      <td>Reference Guidance for use of the Service Not Requested profile can be found <a href="{{site.data.fhir.ver.uscore}}/StructureDefinition-us-core-servicerequest.html#mandatory-and-must-support-data-elements">here.</a></td>
      <ul><li>See the <a href="https://hl7.org/fhir/us/core/sdoh.html">Social Determinants of Health (SDOH)</a> Guidance Page for more information when exchanging Social Determinants of Health (SDOH) Service Requests.</li>
      <li>The <code class="highlighter-rouge">ServiceRequest.category</code> binding must support at a minimum the <a href="{{site.data.fhir.ver.uscore}}/ValueSet-us-core-servicerequest-category.html">US Core ServiceRequest Category Codes</a>.  However, this valueset can be treated as <a href="http://hl7.org/fhir/R4/terminologies.html#extensible">extensible</a> and other category codes can be used instead.</li>
      <li>The <code class="highlighter-rouge">ServiceRequest.code.extension:notDoneValueSet</code> valueset identifies a set of possible coded values representing activities that were not requested, ordered, or performed.</li>
      <li>The <code class="highlighter-rouge">ServiceRequest.subject</code> is Must Support with Must Support reference to QI-Core Patient</li></ul>
  </tr>
  </p>

<a name="usage"><b>Usage</b></a>

<p>The ServiceRequest and ServiceNotRequested profiles represent the positive and
  negative statements for a service request. </p>


<p>
<tr>
    <td>See the <a href="patterns.html">patterns</a> page for implementation and usage patterns.</td>
</tr>
</p>
<a name="examples"> </a>
<h3>Examples</h3>
<p>
<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
        <td><a href="ServiceRequest-negation-example.html">Negation Example with valueset</a></td><td>Service discontinued; indicates that none of the services in the given not done value set were requested.</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
        <td><a href="ServiceRequest-negation-example-code.html">Negation Example with code</a></td><td>Service discontinued; indicates that the given service, by code, was not requested.</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
</p>

<p>Both of these example instances meet measure intent for exclusion as defined in the following example CQL:
</p>

<pre><code>define "Intermittent Pneumatic Compression Devices Not Ordered":
  ["ServiceNotRequested": "Application of intermittent pneumatic compression devices (IPC)"] DeviceNotOrdered
    where (DeviceNotOrdered.reasonRefused in "Medical Reason"
      or DeviceNotOrdered.reasonRefused in "Patient Refusal")
      and DeviceNotOrdered.status in { 'active', 'completed', 'on-hold' }</code></pre>

<p>For a more complete discussion of representation of negation within QI-Core and quality improvement artifacts, see the <a href="index.html#negation-in-qi-core">Negation in QI-Core</a> topic.</p>


</div>
