<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://hl7.org/fhir ../../input-cache/schemas/R5/fhir-single.xsd">
<!--Begin Generated Intro Tag (DO NOT REMOVE)-->
"Must Have", "QI Elements" and "primary code path" are defined in the <a href="index.html#mustsupport-flag">QI-Core Must Support section</a>.<br></br><br></br>

<b>QI Elements:</b>
<ul>
<li>patient: (QI) Patient to whom Device is affixed</li>
</ul>

<b>Primary code path:</b> type
<br></br>
(PCPath) This element is the primary code path for this resource <a href='https://cql.hl7.org/02-authorsguide.html#filtering-with-terminology'>CQL Retrieve</a>
<br></br>
<br></br>

<br></br>
<b>NOTE TO BALLOT REVIEWERS:</b>
<ul>
<li>US Core 7.0, and thus QI-Core 7.0, has a new approach to USCDI requirements.</li>
<ul>
<li>As noted in the US Core 7.0 <a href='https://hl7.org/fhir/us/core/must-support.html#must-support-elements'>Must Support</a> section, US Core 7.0 no longer highlights mandatory (cardinality 1..* or 1..1) and Must Support elements with a (USCDI) indicator as such items must be supported for interoperability.</li>
<li>Those USCDI elements that are not mandatory or Must Support now include an indicator (ADDITIONAL USCDI) in US Core. QI-Core 7.0 does not reference USCDI elements; rather, users should access US Core 7.0 to understand its implementation of USCDI version 4.</li>
</ul>
<li>We invite comments about the approach and suggestions for other options that would also avoid unnecessary noise or reading load to the QI-Core profile representation.</li>
<li>Further, QI-Core 7.0 does not discuss <a href='https://uscdiplus.healthit.gov/uscdi'>USCDI+Quality</a> because at the time of ballot preparation, no published version of USCDI+Quality is available. We seek reviewer advice regarding how QI-Core might address future USCDI+Quality.</li>
</ul>
<br></br>


<!--End Generated Intro (DO NOT REMOVE)-->
  <a name="usage"><b>Usage</b></a>
  <p>FHIR defines the <a href="http://hl7.org/fhir/R4/device.html">Device Resource</a> as a type of a manufactured item that is used in the provision of healthcare without being substantially changed through that activity. The device may be a medical or non-medical device.
  FHIR and US Core further differentiate devices into two “classes”:
  <ul>
  <li>Devices that interact with the human body but do not stay in it are referred to as non-implantable medical devices.</li>
  <li>Implantable devices are those which stay in the human body with a medical objective for an extended period of time, or even a lifetime.<br/>
  <font size="2">[Definition reference: Imam W. How to use ISO 13485:2016 to manage implantable devices, ISO 13485 Blog. July 4, 2016. Available at: <a href="https://advisera.com/13485academy/blog/2017/07/04/how-to-use-iso-134852016-to-manage-implantable-medical-devices/">https://advisera.com/13485academy/blog/2017/07/04/how-to-use-iso-134852016-to-manage-implantable-medical-devices/</a>. Accessed 28 January 2020.]</font>
  </li>
  </ul>
  </p>
  <p>The FHIR Device Resource addresses both implantable and non-implantable devices. US Core only references Implantable Device. QI-Core uses Implantable Device from US Core. Separately, builds directly from FHIR to address non-implantable devices with QI-Core profiles as the device resource.</p>
  <p>Therefore, when creating an expression for an eCQM or a CDS artifact, assure you are using the appropriate Device or Implantable Device resource.</p>
  <p>
  <tr>
      <td>See the <a href="patterns.html">patterns</a> page for implementation and usage patterns.</td>
  </tr>
  </p>
  <a name="examples"> </a>
<h3>Examples</h3>
  <p>
  <table>
    <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td><a href="Device-example.html">General Device Example</a></td>
      </tr>
    </tbody>
  </table>
  </p>

</div>
